FIRST LAST

Bay Area, California · +1-234-456-789 · professionalemail@resumeworded.com · linkedin.com/in/username

Business analyst with five years of experience designing and optimizing [e.g. business processes]. Led teams of 5-15 people across technology, data science, business and design departments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Resume Worded, New York, NY

2017 – Present

Business Analyst

- Managed user engagement analytics strategy, providing first insight into how users interact with our apps on their tablets and mobile devices
- Analyzed company's 24-month sales results to develop five-year monthly projections by revenue and customer type
- Reduced development costs by 25 percent by creating a plan to merge related products into one, more streamlined product.
- Oversaw integration of an external technology solution by leading 5 developers and 9 testers from two companies, resulting in an additional \$1MM of sales.
- Developed an Excel macro and standardized reporting templates, resulting in efficient data collection and a 35% reduction in turnaround time.

Growthsi, San Diego, CA

2015 - 2017

Business Analyst (2016 – 2017)

- Promoted within 18 months due to strong performance and organizational impact (one year ahead of schedule)
- Facilitated three design thinking workshops for end users to identify use cases and develop business requirements

Junior Business Analyst (2015 – 2016)

- Authored business requirements document for proprietary software application: led requirements elicitation sessions (including requirements analysis), solution assessment and validation, use cases and interface/functionality mock-ups
- Interviewed business clients to analyze their business requirements and recommend and design technological improvements to their business processes and operational procedures.

Rofocus, New York, NY

2012 - 2014

Marketing Business Analyst

- Managed redevelopment of internal tracking system in use by 125 employees, resulting in 20+ new features, reduction of 20% in save/load time and 15% operation time.
- Designed and optimized digital marketing campaign on Google AdWords; led to 20% increase in ROI
- **Tip to jobseeker:** Bullet points should be in format [Action Verb] [Accomplishment] [Metric]; e.g. Developed x that led to y% improvement

EDUCATION

Resume Worded University, San Francisco, CA

Master of Engineering; Major in Business Analytics

2015

SKILLS

- SQL
- Microsoft Access
- User Acceptance Testing
- Scrum
- Agile Project Management
- Business Analysis
- Software
 - Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- PRINCE2
- Tableau
- Business
 Intelligence (BI)
- Python